我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
-被令人难以置信的东西杀害  -快跑  巴里
- by something impossible. - Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度
but secretly, I use my speed
打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的人
to fight crime and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
-妈妈  -让我父亲沉冤得雪
- Mom! - And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
你在诺拉·艾伦被谋杀后开创了实验室
You opened your lab after Nora Allen's murder.
你能告诉我你之前在中城
Do you mind telling me what you were doing
是做什么的吗
in Central City before that?
我还以为我们只是两个男人
Here I thought we were just two guys
友好地喝一杯
having a friendly drink.
怎么了
What?
我只是注意到你不怎么笑
I just noticed you don't smile too much.
让你陷入昏迷的那场爆炸
The explosion that put you in a coma
也夺走了我的未婚夫
also killed my fiance.
罗尼
Ronnie!
他是位英雄
He was a hero.
我不希望他是英雄
I didn't want him to be a hero.
我只希望能和他白头到老
I wanted him to be my husband.
不要再找我了
Don't look for me again.
每个人心中都有一位英雄
Everyone has a hero,
有的是他们尊敬或者崇拜的人
someone they look up to or admire,
有的则是自己想成为的人
someone they just wish they could be.
相信英雄很容易
It's easy to believe in heroes.
难的是当英雄不再相信我们
What's hard is when our heroes stop believing in us.
巴里  前面很快就到路口了  快点
Oh, Barry, there's an intersection coming up. Hurry!
这应该能让他们慢下来
This should slow them down.
各位  往哪边走
Guys, which way?
-左边  -右边
- Left. - Right.
-右边  -左边
- Right. -Left.
等等  你们知道
Stop! You both hear you're
彼此说的是两个方向  对吧
telling me two different things, right?
巴里  听我说  仔细听好
Barry, listen up. Listen carefully.
按我说的去做
Here is what you're going to do.
皇后想要到桥那边
Now, the Queen is trying to make it to the bridge,
不过我有条捷径  等一下
but I have a shortcut... wait for it...
左转  左转
And left... left...
-右转  -我看见她了
- right... - I see her!
让她在到达弗里蒙特前往西走
Make her go west before Fremont.
-该怎么做  -我建议让她绕一下路
- Okay, how? - I'd recommend a detour.
国王正朝向州际公路的入口
Now, the King is headed for the entrance to the interstate.
什么入口
What entrance?
好小子
Atta boy.
将...
Check...
拿到钥匙了
Got the keys.
军
mate.
击个掌
Give me some!
效率很高啊  艾伦先生
Efficiently done, Mr. Allen.
-我们得拍张照  -我很确定条例一是
- We need a picture. - Pretty sure rule number one
有秘密身份的人不能穿着战袍
of having a secret identity is not taking pictures of yourself
不戴面具就拍照
in your super suit without a mask on.
拜托  求你了
Oh, come on, please!
绝不外传  只是为了记录一下
This is just for us. This is to document all this.
谁知道呢  或许以后的人们
Who knows? Maybe people in the future
会想知道这是怎么回事
will want to know how all this happened.
如果想要后人知道
All right, well, if you want the future to have
完整的故事  我们都得在照片里
the whole story, then, we all need to be in it.
能先让我化个妆吗
First, let me put on some makeup?
后人才不管你长什么样呢
The future does not care about your makeup.
好了
Okay.
咧嘴笑
Big smiles.
三  二  一
Three...two...one.
这算是自拍吗
Does that count as a selfie?
当然算
Absolutely.
厉害  照得真不错
Sick. Came out good.
谢谢你刚才指挥我
Thanks for talking me through things out there.
不客气
My pleasure.
干得漂亮
Well done.
我得承认  我有些激动  能做...
I have to say it was a bit of a rush feeling like a...
-一名英雄  -是的
- A hero. - Yeah.
你做得很好
You're pretty good at it.
你应该知道搬出去的意思就是
You do realize the whole point of moving out is
不再在家待了  对吧
not being at home anymore, right?
我忘了点东西
I forgot a few things.
又回来住感觉怎么样
So... how is it living back at the house?
巴仔
Bar?
宝贝  我做的意大利面
Babe... spaghetti a la me.
你真的不想留下吃晚饭吗
You sure you don't want to stay for dinner?
谢谢  不过艾迪刷了一整天的房子
Thanks, but Eddie is painting all day
我保证过我要帮他的
and I swore that I would help.
我真的会去帮他刷房子
Although, I'm really just going to do that thing
会把头发和鼻子上
where I get a little paint
都弄上油漆
on my hair and on my nose.
前两天  《中城新闻图报》的人
Someone from Central City Picture News called you
给你打过电话  我把号码贴在冰箱上了
the other day... I left the number on the fridge.
什么  你当时怎么不告诉我
What? Why didn't you tell me?
别激动  我这不告诉你了
Chill! Just did.
我听说皇家同花顺帮的几个人
Hey, I heard that some members of the Royal Flush Gang
被抓进监狱了
are headed to prison.
这尖叫是好事还是坏事
Is that a good scream or a bad scream?
好事  天大的好事
Good! So good!
《中城新闻图报》雇我做记者了
I just got offered a job as a reporter at Central City Picture News.
-太棒了  -他们的主编是我博客的粉丝
- That's awesome! - The editor's a fan of my blog!
-太棒了  -我的天
- That is amazing. - Oh, my God!
天呐
Oh, God.
哈里森·威尔斯
Harrison Wells.
你好
Hello?
我们都知道你做了什么
We both know what you did.
是时候补偿吹笛人了
It's time to pay the Piper!
闪电侠
第一季  第十一集
进来吧
Come in.
乔  我要为这一切道歉
Look, Joe, I apologize for all of this.
这起案件太微不足道了
It just--it really feels like a case of so much for so little.
警方不用来的
The police should not have been called.
这一切发生之前我接到一个恶作剧电话
I got a prank call before all this happened.
感觉这不只是恶作剧啊  博士
This feels like more than just a prank, Doctor.
有人觉得我在去年的粒子加速器爆炸中
There are those who feel I did not suffer enough
遭受的痛苦还不够多
for the particle accelerator explosion of last year,
他们把想法付诸行动了
and some of them act on it.
威尔斯博士  你还好吗
Dr. Wells. Dr. Wells, are you okay?
斯诺博士  我没事  就是有点冷
Dr. Snow, I'm--I'm fine. A little chilly.
除此之外一切无恙  你好  西斯科
Otherwise, I'm fine. Hello, Cisco.
尽量把这里当成自己家吧
Make yourselves at home as best you can.
我要去预定下酒店
I'm gonna make a hotel reservation.
这地方酷爆了
This place is so sick.
你们怎么花了这么久
What took you guys so long?
我们迷路了
We got lost.
我们之前没来过这里
We've never been here before.
真的吗  从来都没来过
Really? Never?
他把私人生活分得比较清
He tends to keep his private life private.
两年前
[拉丁语]
A fronte praecipitium a tergo lupi.
前有悬崖  后有恶狼
A precipice in front, and wolves behind.
换言之  进退两难
In other words, you're between a rock and a hard place.
将军
Check.
国王死了
The King is dead.
将杀
Checkmate.
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells?
就是他
There he is.
哈特利  请允许我为你介绍西斯科·拉蒙
Hartley, allow me to introduce you to Cisco Ramon.
拉蒙先生是我见过的
Mr. Ramon here is one of the finest mechanical engineers
最好的机械工程师之一
I have ever seen.
不敢相信哈里森·威尔斯居然这么说我
I can't believe Harrison Wells said that about me.
我相信他会成为你团队中宝贵的一员
I'm sure he'll prove to be an invaluable member of your team.
-相信我  -我相信你
- Trust me. - You I trust.
我觉得自己不会相信这种人
I don't foresee myself trusting someone
第一天来这个
who showed up to his first day of work
价值数十亿美金的实验室上班
at a billion dollar research facility
却穿着一件T恤  上面写着
wearing a T-shirt that says
"保持冷静  韩先开的枪"
"Keep Calm and Han Shot First."
《星球大战》中  赏金猎人和韩索罗谁先开枪一直存在争议
你能让我们独处一下吗  西斯科
Would you give us a minute please, Cisco?
没问题
Yes, sir.
我知道  你无需向我解释你的雇佣决定
I realize you don't have to explain your hiring decisions to me,
不过就当是为了好玩
but maybe for the sake of a fun exercise,
我们就假装你需要解释吧
we could pretend you did.
我挺看好他的
I have a good feeling about him.
就像我看好你一样
Just as I did about you.
哈特利
Hartley...
你还是我的得意门生
you're still my guy.
任何事和人都不能改变这点
And nothing and no one is ever going to change that.
我巡查了一圈周围街道
I canvassed the street.
没有其它闯入民宅的报告
No other reports of vandalism.
也没有可疑车辆
No strange cars.
听着  威尔斯说事情发生的时候他就在现场
Get this... Wells says he's right there when it happened.
所有的玻璃都在他身边粉碎  而他无法行动
All that glass shattering down around him and he can't walk?
而且他身上一点伤痕都没有
And he didn't have a scratch on him.
没有发现撞击点
There's no point of impact.
没有任何石头  球棒或者硬物
No rock or bat or... any solid object
穿过这些窗子
went through these windows.
感觉像是它们自己碎了
It's as if they just shattered themselves.
这不是什么恶作剧吧
This wasn't some teenage prank?
当然不是
No, it wasn't.
可你不想要我们的帮助
But you don't want our help.
为什么
Why?
因为我知道是谁做的
Because I already know who did this.
哈特利·拉瑟威
Hartley Rathaway.
谁是哈特利·拉瑟威
Who is Hartley Rathaway?
哈特利·拉瑟威是个浪子
Hartley Rathaway is the prodigal son.
而他已经回来了
And he has returned.
哈特利·拉瑟威的科学头脑
Hartley Rathaway possesses one of the finest scientific minds
是我见过最好的之一
I've ever encountered.
他和拉瑟威工业有什么关系吗
Any ties to Rathaway Industries?
他祖父创立了公司  他父亲把公司做大
His grandfather founded the company, his father expanded it,
哈特利生来就是继承公司的
and Hartley here was set to inherit the throne.
-后来发生了什么  -他拒绝继承父母的事业
- What happened? - He came out to his parents.
老贵族们的价值观也很传统
Old money, old values.
当我们相遇时  他和家人很疏远
They were estranged when we met,
但他很聪明  如果不是他
but, brilliant. I couldn't have built
我造不出粒子加速器
the particle accelerator without him.
你们从来没有提过他的名字
You guys have never even mentioned his name.
那是因为哈特利的性格很奇怪
That's because Hartley had a challenging personality.
她的意思是  他差不多是个混蛋
What she means is he was mostly a jerk.
不过  每隔一段时间
But, every once in a while,
他就是个大混蛋
he could be a dick.
哈特利就像其他离群的人一样
Let's just say that Hartley, like many outliers,
不能和同龄人正常交流
had trouble relating to his peers.
可他一直是你的最爱
Yes, but he was always your favorite.
骄子
The chosen one.
他这么称呼自己
He referred to himself like that.
既然你们俩这么亲近  他为何要针对你
So if you two were so close, why would he target you?
哈特利一年前离开了尖端科研实验室
Hartley left S.T.A.R. Labs about a year ago
就在我们
after we had a...
产生了点分歧之后
a disagreement.
什么分歧
About what?
不用担心  我们会阻止他的
Look, don't worry. We'll stop him.
我不会让他伤害你  伤害任何人的
I won't let him hurt you... any of you.
我们先回我的实验室  好吗
Let's get back to my lab, all right?
我本来一辈子都不用再见那个混蛋
I could've gone my whole life without seeing that jerk again.
这地方酷爆了
This place is so dope.
真巧  我们正准备把
What a coincidence. We were thinking of making
"这地方真是酷爆了"作为我们的新标语
"This place is so dope" our new slogan.
如果你真觉得威尔斯博士聘请我是错误的
If you're so convinced Dr. Wells made a mistake
何不证明给他看呢
in hiring me, why don't you try proving it to him?
磁通量是由什么衡量的
Magnetic flux is measured by what?
霍尔效应可以衡量
Hall effect pick up.
串联RC电路的对偶电路
The dual of a parallel R-C circuit?
串联的RL电路
Series R-L circuit.
我可以回答一整天  哥们
I can go all day, pal.
哈特利  看来你遇到对手了
Hartley, it looks like you have met your match.
我是凯特琳·斯诺博士  很高兴认识你
I am Dr. Caitlin Snow. It's very nice to meet you.
西斯科·拉蒙  高兴认识你
Cisco Ramon. Nice to meet you.
别理哈特利  我们都这么不理他
And just ignore Hartley. We all do.
告诉你男朋友在今天下班前给我
Tell your boyfriend I need his specs on the synchotron
同步加速器的配置参数
by end of day.
其实  现在罗尼要下班了
Actually, it is the end of Ronnie's day.
我们今天早走
We are leaving early.
我男朋友要带我出城
My boyfriend is taking me out of town
庆祝我们的一周年纪念日
for our one-year anniversary.
-真好  -谢谢
- That's sweet. - Thanks.
周一见
I'll see you guys on Monday.
再见
See ya.
她看上去不错
She seems nice.
而你不是
You don't.
我给你一周
I give you a week.
最多一周
Max.
《中城新闻图报》
我是爱瑞丝·韦斯特  今天我第一天上班
Hi. I'm Iris West. It's my first day.
看出来了
I can see that.
是吗  有那么明显吗
Really? Does it show?
因为节目开始之前我从没见过你
The fact that I've never seen you before shows.
布里奇先生  你能出席员工会议
Mr. Bridge! Nice of you to make an appearance
真是太好了
at a staff meeting.
我喜欢上好的奶酪酱
I do love a good schmear.
欢迎爱瑞丝·韦斯特  新来的熊宝宝
Everyone, welcome Iris West, our new cub.
有人自愿当她的熊妈妈吗
Anyone want to volunteer to be her mama bear?
梅森  你其实挑了个坏日子出席
Mason, you picked a bad day to actually show up.
-我不做保姆  -我从05年就失去了
- I don't nanny. - I lost the ability
开玩笑的能力  今天  你来
to make a joke back in 05. Today, you do.
截稿时间  所有的新故事要在每天结束前
Deadlines. All new stories are due on my desk
交到我的桌子上
at the end of the day.
对了  我有个主意
Oh, actually, I had an idea for a piece.
在楔石城有个项目
There's this program in Keystone
帮助受过伤的女人重新面对生活
that helps battered women get back on their feet.
听上去真不错  韦斯特
That sounds really great, West.
有没有关于闪电侠的新想法
Actually, any thoughts on a piece about the Flash,
有没有你还没写过的新故事
something you haven't written about yet, something new?
没有  最近没有
No. Not currently.
好吧  大家行动吧
All right. Sally forth, everyone.
行动起来
Sally forth.
每个东西都有自然频率
Everything has a natural frequency.
因为声音是以震动来表现的
And since sound is expressed as a vibration,
如果某种声音的音调
if the pitch of the sound
和某种物体的自然震动频率相吻合  那么...
matches the natural vibration frequency of an object, then...
所以说这可以发生在任何物体上
So, you're saying that can happen to anything,
-不只是玻璃  -对
- not just glass? - Yeah.
我觉得威尔斯家的窗户会碎
I think that's absolutely what happened to the windows
就是这个原因
at Wells' house.
他用了某种声波技术
He's using some kind of sonic technology.
我觉得威尔斯在隐瞒些什么
I'm getting this feeling that Wells is hiding something...
关于拉瑟威这个人
about what's going on with this Rathaway character--
别碰
Don't touch that!
听上去这个哈特利在变恶棍之前
I mean, it sounds like this Hartley guy was a pill
就是个讨厌鬼  所以我...
before he went all super villain, so I--
我理解他为何从来不提他
I get why he never mentioned him.
就好像他从来不提起死去的女友
Like he never mentions his girlfriend that got killed.
没提过
No.
你怎么知道她的
How do you know about her?
他占据了我们大部分的生活
He's taking up a big part of our lives.
我想要更了解他
I wanted to know more about him.
我是说  如果你想更了解他
I mean, if you want to know more about him,
你可以问我
you could just ask me.
听上去你并不没有那么了解他
Sounds like you don't know him as well as you think.
乔  有几个报警电话
Joe. Multiple 911 calls.
拉瑟威工业正遭到攻击
Rathaway Industries is under attack.
巡逻车已经在路上
Sector cars are en route.
-喂  -巴里  我是凯特琳
- Hey. - Barry, it's Caitlin.
我想我知道你为什么打给我了
I think I know why you're calling.
趴到地上
Get down on the ground!
都结束了  拉瑟威
It's over, Rathaway.
你知道我的名字
You know my name.
我也知道几个名字
I know some names too.
凯特琳·斯诺
Caitlin Snow.
西斯科·拉蒙
Cisco Ramon.
哈里森·威尔斯
Harrison Wells.
我可以听到你衣服里传出的电波声
I can hear the radio waves emanating from your suit.
大概有1900兆赫
About 1900 megahertz.
是他们在另一端听着吗
Is that them on the other end, listening?
他们会听到你快死了吗
Are they gonna hear you die?
不  他们会听到我要痛扁你
No. They're going to hear you get your ass kicked.
好吧
Okay.
看上去你不像大家说的那么聪明
Looks like you're not as smart as everyone says.
我聪明到能认清
Smart enough to have figured out
真正的哈里森·威尔斯
who Harrison Wells really is.
我知道他的秘密
You see, I know his secret.
被从头到脚穿着皮衣的人抓到
Being scooped up by a guy clad in head-to-toe leather
是我长久的幻想  所以谢谢了
is a long-time fantasy of mine, so thanks.
好了  好了  大家都在这了
Well, well, well, the gang's all here.
你在这的时间比我想象的更久  西斯科
You've lasted a lot longer than I would've thought, Cisco.
而你跟闪电侠对抗都没有超过十秒
And you didn't last ten seconds against the Flash.
我想称我自己为吹笛人
I was thinking of calling myself Pied Piper.
这里由我给人起名字
Hey! I assign the nicknames around here.
虽然这名字不错
Although that one's not bad.
凯特琳
Caitlin...
我怎没收到婚礼请柬呢
Never did get that wedding invite.
给我闭嘴
Shut the hell up!
走前边
Stay in front of me.
扫描显示你耳中有人造金属物体
The scanner is detecting foreign metallic objects in your ears.
-拿出来  -做不到
- Take 'em out. - I can't.
尖端科研实验室的爆炸对我头部造成了伤害
I suffered head trauma when S.T.A.R. Labs exploded.
我的听力受到了严重的损害
My hearing was severely damaged.
没有那东西  我会承受你无法想象的痛苦
Without these, I'm in pain you can't imagine.
那晚我们都有所损失
We all lost something that night.
将反质子舱改造成监禁牢房
Very clever re-purposing the anti-proton cavities
这想法真是不错
into confinement cells.
肯定是威尔斯的想法
Wells' idea, I'm sure.
实际上是我的
It was mine, actually.
小西斯科
依然在祈求获得主人的认可
你那么聪明  怎么会被关在牢房里
哈特利  别再让事情变得更复杂了
Hartley, don't make this more difficult than it has to be.
我忘了
你不喜欢表达情感
它们就是乱麻
够了  哈特利
Enough, Hartley.
让我们单独待一会
Give us a minute.
等会见  西斯科
See you soon, Cisco.
不可能了
Doubt it!
你的沉默解释了一切
最聋的只有那些不去倾听的人
天啊  真希望我上高中的时候报外语课了
God, I wish I'd taken a language in high school.
你怎么知道我们在与闪电侠合作
How did you know we were working with the Flash?
我写了个六角算法
I wrote a hexagonal algorithm
追踪所有他出现的踪迹
tracking all of his sightings,
推算出了理论上的撤离方位
extrapolating a theoretical exit trajectory.
换句话说  每次他离开犯罪现场时
In other words, every time he ran from the scene of a crime,
都是在向着这个方向跑的
he ran in this general direction.
你真是太聪明了
You are brilliant.
还有  你因我所经受的任何痛苦
And... any anguish you have been through because of me
都不是我有意为之的
was never my intent.
还不错
Not bad...
就一个忠心的道歉来说
as far as heartfelt apologies go.
只是那不是我想要的
Except that wasn't for my benefit.
那都是为了你  闪电侠
That was for you, Flash.
有伟大的哈里森·威尔斯
Feels good to have the great
给你撑腰  感觉挺不错  对吧
Harrison Wells behind you, doesn't it?
但总有一天  这男人会背叛你
But one day, this man will turn on you...
就在一闪之间
in a flash...
即便你也来不及反应
and even you won't see it coming.
我只希望他能给你留个比我好的下场
I only hope that he leaves you in better shape than he left me.
如果你幸运的话  只是会死掉
If you're lucky, you'll only be dead.
因为每一天我都要忍受极大的痛苦
Because every day I have to live with the agonizing,
忍受耳中穿刺般的鸣叫
piercing screaming in my ears.
我差点忘了  我告诉你的宠物
I almost forgot... I told your pet
你那深藏的黑暗的秘密了  哈里森
I know your deep, dark secret, Harrison.
祝你能让他安然接受
Have fun letting him in on that one.
我想你们刚才肯定都在听
I assume you were all listening.
哈特利说的是真的
Well, Hartley was telling the truth.
我没有对你说实话
I have not been honest with you.
对你们都没有说
With any of you.
那加速器...
The accelerator...
哈特利曾经警告过我
Hartley warned me that there was indeed a chance
加速器确实有可能会爆炸
that the accelerator could explode.
他的数据并不是百分之百的确定
His data did not show 100% certainty,
只是会有风险  而且是非常大的风险
just that there was a risk, but it was a real risk.
尽管如此  我认为
And yet I made the decision
我们能够获得的价值...
that the reward...that...
我们能学到  能够达成的
everything we could learn and everything we could achieve,
那些事情...
that all of that...
已经远大于风险了
simply outweighed that risk.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
下一次你拿我们的生命
Then the next time you choose to put our lives,
以及其他我们所爱之人的生命
and the lives of the people that we love,
冒险的时候
at risk,
希望能提前通知一下
I'll expect a heads up.
在那场爆炸后  别人都离开了你的时候
After the explosion, when everyone else left you...
凯特琳和西斯科留在了你身旁
Caitlin and Cisco stood by you.
你欠他们的不只是一个道歉
You owe them more than an apology.
他们很快就会得愿以偿  毕竟哈特利
They might soon get more than that what with Hartley
非常想要把我送向往生
so intent on sending me to the next world.
你说什...
What are--
这不是弥补他们的方式
that wouldn't make it right with them.
你毁了他们的信任  我们的信任
You broke their trust. Our trust.
好啊  老大
Oh! Hi, chief.
-他们是这么叫你的吗  -不  不是
- Is that what people call you? - No. Not really.
听着  有目击者说闪电侠今天挫败了
Listen, eyewitnesses say that the Flash thwarted an attack
市中心的一起犯罪  去调查一下
downtown today. Look into it.
-好吧  -很好
- Yeah, sure. - Great.
梅森  你今天看起来更糟糕了
Mason, you're looking particularly rumpled today.
我们要调查什么
So, what are we working on?
我在调查退休保障部的腐败线索
I am following up on a lead on corruption at the DWP.
你  刚从拉尔金那里得到了任务
You... well, I think you just got your assignment from Larkin,
不是吗
didn't you?
听着  我不蠢  好吗
Look, I'm not stupid, okay?
我知道拉尔金聘我是因为他认为
I know that Larkin hired me because he thinks
我与闪电侠有某种关系
that I have some sort of in with the Flash.
但我是真的想做名记者
But I am serious about being a journalist.
为什么  因为你写过博客吗
Why? Because you write a blog?
我妈妈还写博客呢
My mother writes a blog.
我可能没有什么经验  但我确实有
I may not have a lot of experience, but I do have--
勇气  决心
Spunk? Grit?
进取心
Gumption?
你以为这是鸡仔文学小说吗
What is this, a Chick-Lit novel?
不不不  我的一天才是最糟糕的
No, no, no, I am having the worst day ever.
咱俩不能都有糟糕的一天  好吗
We both can't be having the worst day ever. Okay?
而且我真的想要
And I was really looking forward to getting
好好地吐吐槽
some good complaining in.
那就开始吧
Well, fire away.
好的  实际上我被聘用的真正原因
Okay, well, turns out that the real reason they hired me
是因为他们觉得我跟闪电侠
is because they think I have some sort of connection
有某种联系  但是我没有
to the Flash, which I don't.
不再有了
Not anymore.
我被分去跟梅森·布里奇合作
And I've been teamed up with Mason Bridge,
是位我很景仰的传奇人物  不过他居然
who is a legend, who I admired, before he told me
觉得我是个没用的无能蠢货
I was a worthless, talentless millennial.
毕竟  我们景仰的人不一定是
Well, the people we admire aren't always
我们所期望的那个样子
who we'd like them to be.
说得好
Well said.
所以我完蛋了
So, I'm screwed.
不  听我说
No, look--
如果这个梅森看不出来你是个优秀的记者
if this Mason guy doesn't see what a talented journalist
那他估计也不是什么好作者
you are, then he's probably a lousy writer.
他得过普利策奖
He won the Pulitzer.
好像是两次
Twice, I think.
那好吧
Oh. Good for him.
谢谢你  巴里
Thanks, Barry.
有人相信我的能力  虽然是小事
Having someone believe in me, it's, um--
但对我来说  意义很大
a small...really, really big thing.
威尔斯博士在哪里
Where's Dr. Wells?
不知道  巴里说得对
I'm not sure. Barry was right.
哈特利在利用音频共振原理
Hartley was using sonic resonance.
强度调节器用来测量分贝
The intensity regulator's measuring decibels.
但是你知道哪里奇怪吗
But you know what's weird?
他设定成了最低等级
He had it set to the lowest setting.
-什么意思  -就是说...
- What do you mean? - Well...
他本可以一举彻底摧毁他父亲的建筑
He could've completely destroyed his father's building
如果他想的话
if he wanted to in one blast.
所以  为何不直接毁掉然后离开
So, why not just do it and leave?
为何要留在现场  冒着被抓的危险
I mean, why stick around and run the risk of getting caught?
除非他是故意被抓
Unless he wanted to be caught.
安全监控
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells!
管道监狱有人越狱了
There's been a pipeline breach.
哈特利
Hartley.
留在这里
Stay here.
挺住啊
Ah! Not now.
西斯科  你听得到吗
Cisco, can you hear me?
驱动器已连接
正在传送
威尔斯博士来电
-怎么了  -听我说  哈特利逃跑了
- Hey, what's up? - Listen to me--Hartley escaped.
-他可能在实验室的任何地方  -我就来
- He's loose in the facility. - Okay.
该你了  为什么你今天这么不顺
Okay, your turn--why are you having the worst day...
告诉我  哈里森
Tell me, Harrison.
我还是你的得意门生吗
Am I still you your guy?
你还好吗
Hey! Are you okay?
没事  西斯科和威尔斯博士
Yeah, uh, Cisco and Dr. Wells.
他走了
He's gone.
欢迎回来  拉蒙先生
Welcome back, Mr. Ramon.
我去
Oh, man.
-凯特琳  -别急
- Caitlin? - Hey.
她没事
She's fine.
你需要休息  你有脑震荡
You need to rest. You have a concussion.
你很幸运
You're lucky.
告诉我  你抓到他了
Please tell me you got him.
看来攻击他家族的企业是个幌子
I guess the attack on his family's company was a fake out
-他想被抓  -这样就能
- so we'd catch him. - And give him
-直接进入尖端科研实验室   -为什么
- direct access to S.T.A.R. Labs. - Why?
我本应该看出他图谋不轨的
I should've known he was up to something.
都是我的错
This is my fault.
老弟  这事也怪我
Hey, man. This is on me, too.
我之前不应该离开
I shouldn't have left before--
这件事只怪我
This is no one's fault but mine.
责任归咎于我  不用帮我分担
I earned the blame--I'm not interested in sharing it.
哈特利认为我没有真正的赎罪
Hartley doesn't think I've paid for my crimes.
他说得对
And he's right.
只有我赎罪  他才会停手
He won't stop until I do.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
去重新赢得你们的信任
To earn back your trust.
你进我的粒子加速器干什么
Hmm...now what were you doing in my accelerator?
这不是我们的粒子加速器吗
Thought it was our accelerator.
如果我们打开这个机器  把中城炸了个洞
Because it will be our fault if we turn this thing on
责任我们要共同承担
and blow a hole in Central City.
从地球通往星空的路并不平坦
你在拿这栋楼里所有人的命赌博
You are wagering the lives of everyone in this building.
还有全城人的命
Everyone in this city.
如果你没勇气承认自己可能会出错
If you don't have the courage to admit you could be wrong,
我就替你来
I will do it for you.
哈特利·拉瑟威
Hartley Rathaway...
你在实验室的工作已经结束
your position at S.T.A.R. Labs is terminated.
如果你觉得这能让我闭嘴...
If you think you can shut me up...
我当然可以  哈特利
Oh, I know I can, Hartley.
如果你敢说任何一句
Because if you breathe one word of any kind of
无事实依据的指控
unsubstantiated accusation,
我会确保你唯一能做的物理相关工作
I will make sure the only job you ever get in physics
就只有去高中教物理
is teaching it to high school juniors.
这是怎么回事
What is going on here?
媒体见面会
Press conference.
谢谢各位能抽空前来
Thank you for coming on such short notice.
如果你们读了诺里斯委员会
And for those of you that read the ten-volume report
之前发布的超长报告
issued by the Norris Commission,
我很敬佩你们的耐心
well, I commend you on your tenacity.
你们应该已经知道
You already know, then, the circumstances that led to
关于尖端科研实验室粒子加速器爆炸的情况
the explosion of the S.T.A.R. Labs particle accelerator.
虽然不一定是实情
Or rather, you think you do.
委员会发现  那场惨剧
Now, the Commission's finding was that the catastrophe was
尖端科研实验室  哈里森·威尔斯博士发言
是由一系列事件引起的  没有人想得到
caused by a chain of events that nobody could have predicted,
包括我自己
including myself.
文件传送
真相是...
The truth is...
曾经有人警告过我
I was warned there was a chance
粒子加速器可能会出事
the particle accelerator might fail.
那个人是我曾经的同事
I was warned by a former colleague--
我的朋友
a friend.
我选择忽视他的警告  继续这么做
I chose to ignore the warning and in so doing,
我让你们失望了
I let down all of you.
正如一位新的朋友指出的
As a new friend pointed out...
我辜负了这座城市
I failed this city.
I failed this city
辜负了那些最信任我的人
and I failed those who trusted me the most.
今天我站出来
By coming forward today...
文件传输
是希望走出重获
it's my hope I'm taking the first step toward
尖端科研实验室
他们信任的第一步
regaining that trust.
以及你们的信任
And your trust as well.
有什么问题吗
Are there any questions?
你打算重建
Do you have any intention of rebuilding
粒子加速器吗
the particle accelerator?
韦斯特小姐  你有问题要问我吗
Miss West, do you have a question for me?
我想你还没回答我同事的问题
I don't believe you answered my colleague's question,
威尔斯博士  所以我再问一次
Dr. Wells, so I'll ask it again.
你有任何打算重建
Do you have any intention of rebuilding
粒子加速器吗  无论是现在或者将来
the particle accelerator, either now or in the future?
当然没有
Of course not.
谢谢你的回答  博士
Thank you for your answer, Doctor.
乐意至极
It's my pleasure.
问题到此为止
No further questions.
那算是什么
What was that?
积极进取
Gumption.
哈特利联系过吗
Has Hartley made contact yet?
你怎么那么肯定他会联系我们
What makes you so sure he will?
因为他是哈特利
Because he's Hartley,
他喜欢做总结性发言
and he'll want to have the last word.
西斯科  你该休息了
Cisco, you should be resting.
哈特利愚弄我们去抓他的答案
The answer to why Hartley fooled us into catching him
就在这里  我要找出来
is in here, and I'm gonna find it.
-你没有什么要证明的  -不是的
- You have nothing to prove. - Not true.
你知道我为什么雇佣了你吗  西斯科
Do you know why I hired you, Cisco?
你说你在我身上看到一些东西  我知道
You said you saw something in me.--I know.
我看到的是人性
What I saw was humanity.
你和哈特利  西斯科  你们都是天才
You and Hartley, Cisco, you're both brilliant.
你们都有脑力上的
You both have mental--
火花  但他的天才
sparks. But his brilliance
是从这里的工作经验中提取的
subtracted from the experience of working here,
而你的天才  你的心灵
whereas your brilliance, your heart,
你的热情  幽默感
your warmth, your humor,
是与生俱来的
it just adds to it.
没有什么骄子  西斯科
There is no chosen one, Cisco.
没有第二或者第三最爱的  从来都没有
No second or third favorite. Never was.
只有我们
It's just us.
那是什么
What's that?
开场白不错  哈里森  但这事还没完
Nice gambit, Harrison. But this isn't over.
哈特利  你想怎么样
Hartley, what do you want?
你想怎么样  哈特利
What do you want, Hartley?
我今天已经承认错误了
I already gave my mea culpa today.
这座城市已经怨恨你了
The city already hated you.
你以为我没发现发布会
You don't think I noticed that press conference
只是牺牲象来将军的可悲的一步吗
was a pathetic bishop sacrifice?
不不不  我跟你下过那么多次棋了
No, no, no. I've played with you too many times
不可能让你就这么得手了
to let you get away with that.
这是你  我和闪电侠之间的事
This is between you, me, and the Flash.
你不会想要跟我玩这么
You don't want to play for those kind
大风险的赌注的  哈特利
of stakes with me, Hartley.
事实上  我真的想
Actually, I really do.
怎么样  最后一盘
What do you say? One last game of chess?
你和我都知道最终的胜者
You and I both know that the winner of the game
是犯下倒数第二个错误的人
is the one who makes the next-to-last mistake,
很明显你脑里已经有招数了
and you clearly have a move in mind.
你说得对
You're right.
我已经在棋盘边上了
And I'm already at the board.
所以在我派出几个兵时
So why don't you move your precious scarlet knight...
你为何不派出你宝贵的兵卒呢
While I take out a few pawns.
好吧  西斯科  我要去哪
All right. All right, Cisco, where do I go?
我无法追踪到信号
I can't trace the signal.
他可能是从任何地方
He could be sending his messages
-发送的信号  -西斯科
- from anywhere. - Cisco,
扫描地震活动
scan for seismic activity.
如果哈特利在使用超音冲击
If Hartley's using sonic blast,
共鸣会产生震动
the vibrations could cause tremors.
看  在那  有震动活动但没有断层
Look. Over here. Quake activity but no fault line.
克利夫兰楔石水坝
The Keystone Cleveland Dam.
巴里  别低估了他  他相当聪明
Barry! Don't underestimate him. He's brilliant.
好在我这里有你
Well, good thing I'll have you in here.
车至骑士四
Rook to knight four.
巴里  你必须立刻卸下哈特利的武器
Barry, you need to disarm Hartley immediately.
立刻  你听到了吗
Immediately! Do you hear me?
他很擅长分散注意力
He is a master of distraction.
他很擅长掩盖他的真正目的
He is a master of hiding his true endgame.
你"哈"什么
Ha what?
我知道哈特利
I figured out what Hartley
从尖端实验室偷走什么了
stole from S.T.A.R. Labs,
以及他为什么故意让自己被抓住的原因了
why he let himself get caught.
那"啊哦"的是什么
Which brings us to the...
他有巴里所有的分子扫描数据
He has all the data on Barry's molecular scans.
他要那干嘛
Why would he want that?
他可以得到巴里的频率
He can get Barry's frequency.
巴里  你得离开那了
Barry, you need to get out of there!
你必须立刻离开那里
You need to get out of there immediately!
结束了  你输了
It's over! You lose!
不可思议  他用你取代了我吗
Amazing. He replaced me with you?
十足的傻瓜
Total moron.
我用同样的骗局耍了你两次
I got you with the same trick twice.
看着你和哈里森之间的对话
I got the idea watching you and Harrison chit-chat...
我就想到利用你服装的对讲机来干掉你
to use your suit's own speakers to kill you.
这感觉  是你的器官在撕裂
That feeling? That's your organs shearing apart.
你卸下我的武器时触发了频率
And you activated the frequency when you disarmed me.
在象棋中  我们叫这闪击
In chess, we call that a discovered attack.
你发现时已经太晚了
You don't see it until it's too late.
对吧  哈里森
Right, Harrison?
巴里的生命体征数据降到最低点了
Barry's vitals are bottoming out.
我们得想办法做点什么
We need to do something.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
巴里在水坝的公路上  现在是上下班高峰期
Barry's on the travel road of the dam, at rush hour,
周围会有很多车辆
surrounded by cars.
许多车上都有卫星广播
Many of those cars are going to have satellite radio.
访问卫星
卫星把信号发送至车上
Satellite sends a signal to the car,
-从喇叭放歌...  -我知道
- song comes out the speaker... - Yes! I know
卫星广播的运作原理  可这有什么帮助
how satellite radio works! How does that help?
我要让卫星发送一些
Well, I'm gonna have the satellite send something
不是歌曲的东西
other than a song.
改变任务
哈特利将会听到些
Hartley is about to hear something
他没想过会听到的声音
he was not expecting--
而声波会与这些声音的频率相遇
a sound wave that will meet the frequency of them
毁掉他的武器
and destroy his weapons.
卫星频率改写
你看起来也不怎么特别了
You don't seem so special anymore.
鉴于打败你是这么容易
Given how easy it was to bring you down,
不知道哈里森是否会想念你
I wonder if Harrison will even miss you.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
将军
Checkmate.
巴里  能听到我说话吗
Barry, can you hear me?
勉强能
Sort of!
-好了  -感觉如何
- Okay! - How do you feel?
没事  我有点耳鸣
Fine! I mean there is a little ringing in my ears,
除此之外  我没事
but other than that I'm good, so...
你说话很大声
You're speaking very loudly.
-抱歉  -没事  耳鸣会消失的
- Sorry. - It's okay, it'll pass.
-干得漂亮  -谢谢
- Nice moves. - Thank you.
不客气
Anytime.
我想我要听从医生的建议
I think I'm gonna take my doctor's advice
躺下休息一会
and go lie down.
这注意不错
What a great idea!
天  我有种宿醉乘十倍的感觉
Man, I feel like I'm hung over times ten.
毫不惊讶
I'm not surprised.
对我来说很难
It's difficult for me...
承认我做错了
to admit when I'm wrong.
尤其是在整个城市的面前  还有...
Certainly, in front of an entire city but also...
还有在我最亲密的朋友面前
Also to my closest friends.
所以我希望有一天
So I hope one day
能让你恢复对我的信任和信念
to restore your trust and faith in me.
那天就是今天
That day was today.
不是每个英雄都带面具
Not every hero wears a mask.
有的英雄用最简单的方法来拯救世界
Some heroes save the day in the simplest of ways.
只要在身边支持就行了
By just being there for us...
或是让我们了解我们的信念
or letting us know we're believed in.
如果今天我是英雄  那不是因为我的速度
If I'm any sort of hero today, it's not because of my speed.
而是因为我从身边的人身上学到的
It's because I learned how from the people in my life...
每一个人身上
all of them.
克利夫兰水坝袭击事件
今天的新闻发布会真是了不起
Man, that press conference today was something else.
威尔斯博士  这么做需要很大的勇气
Dr. Wells... took a lot of guts to do that.
这一点我认可他
I have to give him that.
他有属于自己的时刻
He has his moments.
怎么了
What's up?
对你来说一定很艰难吧
Must have been hard for you.
什么  长得这么帅气吗
What? To be this handsome?
把我抚养成人
Raising me.
一个喜欢数学和化学的小孩
Well, a kid who loved math and chemistry,
午后乐趣只是
whose idea of a fun afternoon was
在车库里做试验
doing experiments in the garage.
一点也不困难
Couldn't have been easy.
自从我开始上预修课程  你根本
As soon as I started AP classes, you had
没法帮助我做家庭作业
you had no clue how to help me with my homework.
-是不容易  -你肯定总是觉得
- No. - You must have always felt like
你在和理查德·道金斯和尼尔·泰森一较高下
you were competing with Richard Dawkins and Neil Tyson and...
理查德·道金斯  牛津大学动物学家
尼尔·泰森  美国天文学家
还有亨利·艾伦
Henry Allen too.
可是他们没有一个人
But, look, none of them-- no one--
能取代你的位置
could ever replace you.
包括威尔斯
Not even Wells.
-好了  家里见  -好
- All right, I'll see you at home. - All right.
-艾迪  -巴里
- Hey, Eddie. - Hey, Barry.
你查到了什么
Hey, what'd you find out?
我照你说的搜查了威尔斯的整个房子
I searched Wells' entire house like you said.
可是什么也没发现
There was nothing.
你确定你要这么做吗
Are you sure you want to do this--
调查威尔斯
Investigate Wells?
百分之百确定
100%
这次你那邪恶的助听器也无法助你逃脱
Your evil hearing aids won't help you escape this time.
所以我劝你趁早适应
So I'd get comfy.
你肯定很享受吧  西斯科
You must be enjoying this, Cisco.
-是的  -那好吧
- I am. - Ah, well,
如果你害怕的话  我无法想象
if that scares you, I can't imagine
等你打开门  放我出去之后
how you're gonna feel when you open up these doors
又会作何感受
and let me out of here.
可能是我要聋了  因为我发誓
Maybe I'm going deaf, 'cause I could've sworn
你刚说了我会放你出去
you just said I'm gonna let you out.
而且那一刻很快就会到来
And very soon too.
我为什么要这么做
Why would I ever do that?
因为我知道罗尼·雷蒙德的下落
Because I know where Ronnie Raymond is.
我知道那晚他到底发生了什么事
I know what really happened to him that night.
我还知道怎么救他
And I know how to save him.
警告  光速粒子输出已超出可接受容限
Warning! Tachyon output has passed acceptable tolerance range.
不推荐继续接触
Continued exposure is not recommended.
增加到最大限度  吉迪恩
Increase to maximum, Gideon.
增加到最大限度  博士
Increasing to maximum, Doctor.
速度力量吸收在百分之35  并且上升
Speed Force absorption at 35% and rising.
我现在不稳定  我无法坚持我的速度
I'm not stabilizing. I can't hang on to my speed.
来而复返  我无法控制
It comes and goes, and I can not control it.
吉迪恩  超光速粒子设备还有多久能用
Gideon, for how much longer is the Tachyonic device viable?
运算结果不确定
Calculations inconclusive.
-抱歉  博士  -没关系  吉迪恩
- I'm sorry, Doctor. - Oh, that's okay, Gideon.
这本来也就是临时的解决办法
This was only meant to be a temporary fix.
真正的尾声即将来临
The real endgame is almost here.